Fabio Ferreira

http://www.fabiosferreira.com.br fabio.ferreira@ifsudestemg.edu.br

CURRICULUM VITAE

I am an assistant professor at the Federal Institute of the Southeast of Minas Gerais and a Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science at Federal University of Minas Gerais (DCC-UFMG). At UFMG I work in the ASERG group under supervision of professor Marco Tulio Valente. I am broadly interested in developing use-inspired research in software engineering, with focus on techniques and methods for building and evolving complex software systems.

Previously, I completed my master degree in Computer Science under supervision of professor Carina Frota Alves at the Federal University of Pernambuco (CIn - UFPE) in 2016.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Minas Gerais – Belo Horizonte - Brazil

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Computer Science, 9.46/10 2019 - Expected 2023

Federal University of Pernambuco - Recife - Brazil

Master of Science (M.S), Computer Science, 9.5/10 2014 - 2016

Federal Institute of the Southeast of Minas Gerais - Barbacena - Brazil

Bachelor of Technology - Internet Systems

2006 - 2008

Federal Institute of the Southeast of Minas Gerais - Barbacena - Brazil

Technical Course in Informatics

2003 - 2004

PUBLICATIONS

FERREIRA, F.; SILVA, LUCIANA L.; VALENTE, MARCO TULIO. **Software Engineering Meets Deep Learning: A Mapping Study**. *In: 36th ACM Symposium On Applied Computing (SAC)*, 2021, Gwangju, South Korea.

FERREIRA, F.; SILVA, LUCIANA L.; VALENTE, MARCO TULIO. **Turnover in Open-Source Projects: The Case of Core Developers**. *In: 34th Brazilian Symposium on Software Engineering (SBES)*, 2020, Natal, Brazil.

DINIZ, JOAO P.; CRUZ, D.; FERREIRA, F.; SILVA, CLEITON; FIGUEIREDO, Eduardo. **GitHub Label Embeddings**. *In: 20th IEEE International Working Conference on Source Code*

Analysis and Manipulation (SCAM), 2020, Adelaide, Australia. New Ideas and Emerging Results Track.

XAVIER, L.; FERREIRA, F.; BRITO, R.; VALENTE, MARCO TULIO. **Beyond the Code: Mining Self-Admitted Technical Debt in Issue Tracker Systems**. *In: 17th International Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR)*, 2020, Seoul, South Korea.

FERREIRA, F. S.; ALVES, C. F.; CAVALCANTI, ROSA CANDIDA. **R-BPM: Uma Metodologia para Gerenciamento de Processos de Negócios Consciente dos Riscos**. *iSys: Revista Brasileira de Sistemas de Informação*, v. 9, p. 5-37, 2016.

FERREIRA, F. S.; ALVES, C. F.; PINTO, R. C. C. A Risk Management Model Integrated with BPM Lifecycle. 13th International Conference on Information Systems and Technology Management (CONTECSI), 2016, São Paulo, Brazil.

TEACHING

Undergraduate

Web Application Development	2016 - Current
Information Systems Management	2016 - Current
Visual Programming	2016 - Current
Distributed applications	2016 - Current

Technical High School on Informatics

Systems Analysis	2016 - Current
Web Page Development	2016 - Current
Web Programming	2016 - Current
Operating systems	2016 - Current

WORK EXPERIENCE

Information Technology Analyst

Federal Institute of the Southeast of Minas Gerais - IF Sudeste MG 2010 - 2016

Lead Developer

Secretariat of Professional and Technological Education - SETEC 2011 - 2012

Information Technology Analyst

Computer Center - Federal University of Minas Gerais - CECOM UFMG 2009 - 2010

Full Stack Developer

Secretariat of Professional and Technological Education - SETEC 2006 - 2009